Bye-bye, Kobato!
Okay, see you on Monday!
I'm sorry!
What is it with you, always?
Are you all right?
Never mind, just get out of my way.
I'm going to be late.
Are you working tonight, too?
Well yeah.
Oh, Kobato.
Thanks for your help.
Um, is there anything I can help you with?
No, I'm fine. You can go home now.
Part-time work
Job information
Kobato.
What should I do?
Even the most obvious of things
Are always such a challenge
I want to laugh when I'm happy
And sing whenever I want
Is all
They say my dreams will come true someday
But when will "someday" come?
I can't wait forever
On "1, 2, 3!" I'll spread open my arms
And let the light gather around me
Where is it?
Please tell me what I can do
I make the most of getting hurt
And run with all my might
Despite how many dozens of times I fall
And start crying
I surprise myself
In how much I believe in tomorrow
...Detective Kobato Hanato.
Wow...
I didn't realize there were so
many different kinds of jobs.
What do you plan to do with that book? Ouch!
What else? I'm going to find a job!
Just like Fujimoto!
You want to help in any little way to
pay back that debt. Is that is?
Yes!
Like deliver newspapers in the fresh morning air.
You always oversleep in the morning.
Ah, well then...
How about delivering
pizzas to everyone's homes?
You will get lost and that's for certain.
W-Well then...
Maybe I could help people move.
I can just see you breaking an expensive vase.
What?! Then what kind of job should I look for?
Don't ask me!
I give up!
Ioryogi-san!
Good evening!
Yes?
Oh no...
It's got torn.
The poor thing.
Sorry.
That's all right.
There. All done.
Thank you very much!
No problem.
Oh! There's one other favor I wanted to ask.
Oh! The umbrella man!
Oh yes, from the other day.
Thank you for your kindness that day.
Don't mention it.
Oh? So I see you already know each other.
Yes. Let me introduce myself properly.
I'm Ueda, the manager of this shop.
I'm Kobato Hanato!
Kobato lives in our building.
Her regular job is helping out
at Yomogi Kindergarten.
She said she was looking for a
part-time job, so I thought of this shop.
Is that right?
Well we could certainly use your help,
in particular during the busy weekends.
At least until my hands get better.
Look at the shape they're in.
What happened?
Well... I can be clumsy sometimes and...
She apparently injured herself the other day.
Are you okay?
Mhm. It's just that the manager has to also
cover for me when it gets busy.
Kobato, you would be a great help.
Yes, Mr. Manager, I would very
much like to help out.
And you... uh...
I'm Yumi Omura. Welcome aboard, Kobato.
I hope you enjoy your job, Kobato.
Yes!
I'm changed!
Oh good. The uniform fits you perfectly.
So, what would you like me to do?
Um... Well, you could begin by
cheerfully welcoming customers?
Hi! Good afternoon!
Ah, y-yes, something like that.
Yes!
Then after you take their order
put the cakes in those boxes.
These here?
I'll handle the cash register.
You take their money.
And "Thank you very much!" Right?
That's right!
Hello.
Hello!
Well then, shall we give it a try?
Yes!
Umm... I'll have the strawberry shortcake...
the Mont Blanc cake... and um...
Strawberry shortcake, Mont Blanc, cheese...
Umm... I'll have the strawberry shortcake...
the Mont Blanc cake... and um...
Strawberry shortcake, Mont Blanc, cheese...
the cheesecake... no not that, the apple pie.
Oh and that lemon tart.
apple... lemon... uhh...
the cheesecake... no not that, the apple pie.
Oh and that lemon tart.
apple... lemon... uhh...
Yes and one of those cream puffs, please.
Uh... um...
Strawberry shortcake, Mont Blanc, apple pie,
a lemon tart and a cream puff.
What a memory! I'm impressed.
Would you put them in a box Kobato?
Ah, yes.
Um... strawberry shortcake...
I'm so sorry!
Relax. Will you get another one?
Y-Yes.
Kobato are you okay?
Y-Yes!
And also the Mont Blanc and...
Apple pie, lemon tart and cream puff.
It's ready!
Then finally...
Thank you very much!
Thank you, cheerful shop assistant.
Was that okay?
Yes. I'm sure you'll be all right once
you get the hang of things.
Hello!
Huh?
Kobato!
Marina and Marina's mother!
Hello!
Hello.
Kobato is a cake shop worker!
Yes. Today I'm a cake shop worker.
I'm jealous.
Which cake would you like?
We came to pick up my birthday cake today!
Wow, it's your birthday?! Happy Birthday!
Kobato, can you wrap it up for them?
Yes!
Here you go.
Here you are. Sorry to keep you waiting.
Thank you, Kobato.
Thank you very much!
See you!
What's the matter?
Happy Birthday Marina
Why is this here?
You may have put the wrong cake in the box!
I'll try and catch Marina!
Marina!
Kobato, are you okay?
Y-Yes...
Bakery Tirol
Hello!
I'll have that and this one over here.
Bakery Tirol
Right!
Kobato, that customer's asking for
Mont Blanc and cheesecake.
Bakery Tirol
Oh no! I'm sorry!
I'm all tired out.
Good job, Kobato.
Oh, thank you for your help!
Here's something for you.
Huh? Wow, thank you!
Ioryogi-san will be pleased!
Io?
He's a stuffed doll in front of people.
I'll be looking forward to your help tomorrow.
Are you sure? You don't mind if I come again?
Why, of course not.
Yumi, thanks. You can go too.
Oh but there's still cleanup to do.
I'll take care of that. Your hands aren't
healed yet. Don't push yourself.
Okay...
Well then, Mr. Ueda. Good nigh...
Good night, sir!
Oh yes. Have a good night.
Is something the matter?
No. It's nothing.
But Yumi, you seem to be
worried about something.
I was just thinking about Mr. Ueda.
Mr. Ueda?
There seems to be something on his mind.
I asked him about it once, but he
just said, "It's nothing."
Oh is that right?
The shop is doing well.
Then what could it be that's bothering him?
I wonder if he's in debt.
What?
Yomogi Kindergarten is in
trouble because of that.
Kobato, is that why you decided
to start working with us?
Yes!
That is admirable.
Oh no. What I'm doing is nothing
compared with Ms. Sayaka and Fujimoto.
I just wanted to help in any way that I can.
I wish I could help Mr. Ueda.
Now this is incredibly delicious.
It's tough not being able to help
out when you want to, isn't it?
I'm going to find out what's bothering Mr. Ueda.
Well, fine, but don't stick your nose
in too far and get yourself fired.
I won't be able to have any more
of this delicious cake.
Oh, but it might be good to work
at different kinds of places.
Sushi!
How about a steakhouse?!
Or classy Chinese cuisine?!
So Kobato, where do you plan to work next?
I plan to stay at the cake shop for awhile!
Good morning!
Good morning, Kobato.
Good morning.
Will you please line these cookies on the shelf?
Yes, sir!
Oh, please take care of things out here.
Did he just sigh, looking at me?
Huh? Did he do that?
I wonder why.
Could I have something to do with his problems?
I'm going to ask Mr. Ueda what the problem is.
Trust me!
Are you sure? Then... ask
him nonchalantly, okay?
Okay! Kobato is ready!
Excuse me...
Kobato?
Yes. Um, actually I...
There's something I want
to nonchalantly ask you!
Kobato?!
What is it?
I'm wondering. Is there perhaps
something that is worrying you?
Everything is fine. Nothing's worrying me.
But...
Yumi told me that you were
deep in thought sometimes,
or that you seemed like you
wanted to say something.
That something's wrong.
It's nothing that Yumi should
be concerning herself with.
That's what he says.
That makes me more curious than ever.
Good morning.
Oh?
Kobato?
Ms. Sayaka!
What are you doing here?
She's helping us out until my hands get better.
Oh is that right?
Would you like some cake?
I'm heading over to Chitose's place for a visit
and I thought I'd pick something up for her.
It's been a while since I bought
something from Bakery Tirol.
You once ordered a birthday cake
for your husband, didn't you?
Uh... yes...
Ms. Sayaka's husband?
I guess that means that she's
married and has a husband.
But I've never met him.
Maybe they split up then.
Ms. Sayaka seemed lonely.
Don't ask her about this openly.
Why shouldn't I?
There are some things people
don't want to talk about.
You're keeping quiet about working to
help the kindergarten, aren't you?
Everyone has their own secrets.
Do you think that the Bakery Tirol manager
is keeping something secret too?
But Yumi really wants to know. So in
that case, what should be done?
Investigate secretly, I guess.
A job that I doubt is suited for a Dobato, though.
But I'll do my best!
Thank you very much!
Being secretive... I guess...
Hey, it's Kobato!
What are you doing?
I'm secretly investigating.
Wow, cool!
Like a detective!
A detective?
Wow...
So this is what a detective does.
Yeah.
That's right.
A detective investigates a lot, like
motive and alibi, proof and so on,
asks a lot of questions and follows
people and stuff like that, right?
Cool!
We'll help!
No. A detective works alone!
Oh, I see.
You're going way off tangent here!
Thank you very much!
Um, excuse me!
Um, today, I'm a detective!
What? A detective?
Did you notice anything unusual at Bakery Tirol?
No, not really.
Uh, are you working on a case?
Yes. It's the case of something
worrying the manager!
Something is...
...worrying the manager?
Does anything come to mind?
Uh, we might not be the right people to ask.
Isn't there anything?
Bakery Tirol's cakes are very popular.
I'd say it's not work-related.
Oh I see.
Thank you very much!
I-I think we'd better be going now.
I'm out of here. I'm going to use
my own investigation network.
Investigation network?
What?!
Why the heck would I involve myself in that?
Be generous, Genko.
If you're looking for a love
counselor, try someone else!
Well then I guess I'll just pick
this up and head home.
Why you! You only came here to eat
my Baumkuchen, didn't you?!
You're absolutely right.
What?!
See ya!
Good night.
Yumi!
Kobato?
Good evening.
What are you doing?
I'm a detective!
What?
What I have found out so far is
that Bakery Tirol's cakes
are very popular and that the
manager is probably worried
about something other than work.
Oh! But Mr. Ueda always gives the little
children some chocolate for free.
He's always considerate of
the health of other people.
And everybody likes his cakes.
That's how much I found out.
And I even got some chocolate myself!
Mr. Ueda is kind to everyone.
Yumi. We'll begin tailing him now!
What?!
Kobato, forget it. Let's go home.
Huh?
But...
I wonder if he's meeting someone.
We really shouldn't be following
him like this, but...
Oh, someone has arrived.
Who could that be?
Is it someone you don't know?
Never seen her.
Maybe they're on a date!
And maybe that's why he
couldn't tell me about her.
What should I do, Kobato?
Please settle down, Yumi!
Mr. Ueda will notice us.
Yumi?
Yumi!
Wait!
Mr. Ueda.
Kobato!
Oww...
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
But what I want to know is, who was
that person you were with?
Actually that was an interview.
For a job at the shop.
A job? Why?
Kobato's now helping out on the
weekends, but frankly,
I haven't been able to give
you any time off, Yumi.
Time off?
You must be very exhausted.
And you working under such conditions
probably had something to do with your injury.
Mr. Ueda... Then, that's what
you were worried about?
Yes.
You always work so hard for me, and I feel like
I've been taking advantage of that. I'm sorry.
Oh, no. I really enjoy working with you.
I don't need any time off.
I enjoy talking with the customers who
come to buy your cakes every day.
And I enjoy greeting you every day!
Besides, my injury...
Well...
That is very cute.
Did you make this?
Yes. I hurt myself all over
while practicing baking cakes.
I wanted to help you out, so I decided to learn.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
Do you mind if I try it?
Ah, sure.
It's good.
Really?
I've hired a new girl, which gives you more time.
We can study baking cakes together.
Yes!
So, the case has been solved?
Yes. Detective Kobato has solved the case.
The manager wanted to give Yumi more time
off... but Yumi wanted to help him more.
They were both being considerate for the other.
It was a very beautiful case.
Oh well. I can't complain.
And I got my Baumkuchen.
That Baumkuchen is not from Bakery Tirol, is it?
And you brought it home once before.
Does this have something to do with
your "investigation network"?
Oh, that reminds me! Your score this time!
I got to eat some cake, so I'll be extra
sweet and give you one hundred!
Really?
Fujimoto!
What is it?
I brought something for you!
Huh?
It's chocolate from the shop
that offered me a job.
A job? You?
I'll keep trying my best! So please take some
time off, or go to classes, or whatever.
Well, I can't imagine anything good
happening with you trying your best.
You are not nice...
Hey.
Don't try too hard to the extent
that you make yourself sick.
Could you possibly be worrying about me?
Not at all.
Thank you very much.
Right now, do something about
that scribble on your face.
Th-This is my hundred points!
What are you talking about? It's scribble.
No it isn't! You only get fifty
points because you're mean!
What on earth are you talking about?
Everyone dreams of flying
But they let gravity trick them
Honestly, everyone is already able to fly
I bet the reason that child looks so terribly sad
Is because he
Accidentally lost his shadow somewhere
In that case
If I could just tell you, "Thank you,"
And you laugh and reply, "Thank you"
That exchange would fill you with joy
It would make you feel so happy
There's nothing to worry about
Since we're together
It's strange how I'm crying
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...Silver Eyes.
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...Silver Eyes.